# **Thewodros Bekele**

Web Developer

Email: <u>bekele.thewodros@gmail.com</u>

Phone: 571-977-9392 Fairfax, Virginia

# **Summary**

I have 6+ years of experience in developing, enhancing, and maintaining software applications and highly effective at optimizing user experiences and improving site functionality by utilizing advanced abilities in Git & GitHub, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, typescript, jQuery and SQL. Resourceful and industrious professional with an analytical and detail-oriented mindset.

#### **Technical Skills**

Web Development	HTML, CSS (Cascading Style Sheets), Bootstrap, JavaScript, OOPS,		
	TypeScript, jQuery, Node.js, Vue.js, React, Mocha		
Tools	Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, GIT, GitHub, Heroku		
Databases	MySQL		
Methodologies	Waterfall, Agile		
Operating Systems	Windows, Mac OS		

# **Project Experience Summary**

<b>Companies Worked For</b>	From – To	Roles
Bank of America	August 2020 - Present	Web Developer
Capgemini Group, Sogeti	February 2018 – July 2020	Web Developer
Right Reason Technologies	March 2016 – January 2018	Junior Front-End Developer

# **Project Experience Details**

# Bank of America, USA Role: Web Developer

August 2020 to Present

I work with teams to standardize the bank best practices and work alongside a team of other developers in creating, maintaining, and updating websites. Create documentations, assist and conduct training for teams ensuring sustainability and maintainability of team's daily activities for successfully client deliverables.

#### Responsibilities

- Website and software application designing, building, or maintaining.
- Code websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.

- Planning website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML,
  JavaScript and JSON coding.
- Provide front-end website development using WordPress and other editing software.
- Discuss site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans and budgets.
- Built and style new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.
- Develops user-friendly webpages based on the best practices for UI/UX, including mobile responsive website(s), speed and scalability
- Conduct functional testing over course of web development lifecycle.
- Conduct testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Responsible for design, programming, quality control, security, testing, debugging, and documentation tasks for assigned projects
- Identify problems uncovered by customer feedback, testing and correct or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Integrating regulatory and compliance standards into product designs.
- Maintain banking application systems in operation, including providing IT (Information Technology) solutions, tasks related to debugging, identifying, troubleshooting application issues, and fixing the application issues.
- Collaborate with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Work in Agile Environment, active participation in sprint planning and tasking, status update to the team on daily stand-up calls and huddle sessions with Mentor.

### Capgemini Group, Sogeti

#### February 2018 to July 2020

#### Role: Web Developer

As a junior web developer, I was responsible for assisting with the creation of websites and updating existing web applications using scripting languages. I work under the supervision of senior developers, assisting with coding, testing, design adjustments, and client reviews.

#### Responsibilities

- Worked in a cross-discipline team, using agile development methodology that requires active participation in all team's activities, focusing on a common team goal
- Supported the development that will grow business and introduce new trading opportunities in a timely manner
- Provided technical and operational support on all components of the trading platform and provide technical and operational support
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS.

- Designed and implemented web components across new and existing designs.
- Analyzed, prioritized and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.
- Studied user requirements and implemented requirements into solutions.
- Established and own our strategies for Security, Performance & Testing
- Defined, measured and owned our Continuous Delivery strategy
- Collaborated with project managers, testers, end-users, and distributors.
- Worked in multi-project environment along with other intern groups. Team collaboration and effective communication with other Developers and Stakeholders.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Ability to work with git and GitHub
- Independent learner who loves to work in a fast-paced environment
- Used user feedback to identify and correct problems with a client's website.

#### **Right Reason Technologies**

#### March 2016 to January 2018

#### **Role: Junior Front-End Developer**

My role in my team as a front-end developer are implementing visual as well as interactive elements, which are helpful in engaging users by making use of their web browser when making use of a web application which provide tools for districts and schools that improve the success of teachers and students. Our team is responsible for the UI/UX wireframe translation into the real code, which will help produce the product's actual visual-based elements.

#### Responsibilities

- Built Responsive web applications using HTML5, JavaScript and CSS code based on wire frames / Visual Design
- Worked with UX/UI designers to promote brand consistency and interface guidelines
- Coded, tested and implemented front-end solution to meet business requirements
- Maintained code quality and best practices across the Front-End team
- Creation of intuitive, robust, and reusable user interfaces using VanillaJS and modern frameworks
- Translated UI/UX designs wireframes to actual code that produce visual elements of the applications
- Worked with the UI/UX designer and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation
- Stayed abreast of the latest technologies available in the world of Web Development
- Worked closely with other project team members (engineers, designers and project managers)
- Developed front-end templates, and help integrate into an enterprise

- Delivered high-quality outputs at all stages of development, from documentation to code
- Communicated clearly with both clients and colleagues
- Worked within project timelines
- Managed the office's Website

## **Education**

- Generation USA, Certification: Web Development
- Bachelor of Arts: Management and Leadership

## **Certifications**

- W3School | JavaScript Developer
- Codecademy | TypeScript | Node.js | Unit Testing with Mocha | PHP | GitHub | React | jQuery |
  MySQL